ASSISTANT SCIENTIST II

Professional Summary

Quality control chemist with 3+ yrs. experience working in laboratory settings, in quality control departments and testing raw material, in process and finished goods against specifications using wet chemistry techniques. Quality Engineer reviewing and updating SOPs, leading continuous improvement teams, daily testing of finished products using internal and 3rd party laboratories and experience with Root Cause Analysis and Corrective Action Preventative Action Databases. Working knowledge of chemistry lab methods including; FT-IR, Karl Fisher, HPLC and Wet Chemistry Techniques. Experience in cGMP and cGLP environments. Vast computer software knowledge including MS Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Visio) and SAP. Certified in Internal Auditing - NSF & SQF (Safety and Quality Standards). Working experience with BRC, FDA, CLIA, HIPAA, OSHA Safety & DOT compliances.

Professional Experience

Jacobs Engineering Group Inc. Las Vegas, NV Assistant Scientist II 03/2015 to 11/2015

- Performed sampling for incoming inspection of API and excipients held in quarantine for release testing.
- Performed inspection of packaging components and released for use following cGMP regulations.
- Tested in process batch samples following USP and EP methodologies.
- Cleaning verifications using Total Organic Carbon analyzers.
- Calibrating and troubleshooting testing equipment.
- Reported scientific results to support regulatory submission FDA inspection readiness program for the analytical laboratory.

Ball Corporation Bangalore, IN Scientist I (Contractor) 01/2015 to 03/2015

- Staged, pulled and performed stability testing on finished product samples.
- Performed test procedures following stability protocols.
- Prepared, reviewed SOP's, validation and stability documents.
- Prepared and reviewed change controls Logging in and testing of raw materials, in process samples and finished samples.
- Test procedures used included Karl Fisher Volumetric & Coulometric, FTIR, HPLC using Chemstation, pH, Manual & Auto Titrations, Visual inspections tests following SOPs.
- Good Documentation Practices, cGood Manufacturing Practices, Good Lab Practices.

Alcon City, STATE Chemistry Quality Analyst (Contractor) 03/2014 to 07/2014

- Performed analytical testing on raw material, in process and finished samples.
- Performed validation studies to support method developments Monthly stability pulls, analytical testing and comparison to trend analysis for various storage conditions.
- Prepared summary reports from laboratory data.
- Performance verification and system suitability testing.
- Peer reviews of documentation and sample preparations.
- Test methods used: Karl Fisher, pH, Viscosity, Osomometer, Clarity, Turbidity, Particle size analysis using Microtrac, Visual inspections tests following SOPs and Methodologies.
- Customer complaint investigations.
- Use of LIMS (Laboratory Information Management System).

Dart Container Corporation City, STATE Quality Technician 07/2012 to 02/2014

- Performed plant wide complaint, deviation and non-conformance investigations through Root Cause Analysis and CAPA system.
- Introduced and established process controls on machine formers using process capability tests.
- Oversaw internal auditing system through scheduling, planning and training of documented SOPs and Work Instructions of product and system audits in accordance to cGMPs.
- Oversaw calibration/verification activities for all quality department measurement and test equipment.
- Prepared plant quality trend indicators and pareto charts to identify problem areas and support Continuous Improvement projects.
- Successfully led a Continuous Improvement team to a 50% reduction in customer complaints in a year.
- Led the implementation team for initial BRC certification; a global leading safety and quality certification program for food and food packaging and successfully certified the plant in 6 months.
- Trained and directed a cross functional HACCP team Successfully met key matrices through reduction in customer complaints, and implementation of CAR effectiveness and timeliness.
- Led the reduction of on hold inventory through disposition of non-conformances, schedule of inspections and weekly inventory audits.

Avero Diagnostics City, STATE Cytology Lab Assistant 01/2009 to 06/2012

- Experience working in a laboratory setting under minimal to no supervision in receiving, accessioning and processing biological specimen for diagnosis.
- Cleaning and maintaining laboratories and lab equipment.
- · Performed data entry of patient and specimen information including transcription of patient history.
- Performed technical procedures such as collecting, measuring and recording specimen data.
- Trouble shooting lab equipment used to stain and process slides.
- Trained in CLIA, HIPAA, OSHA and DOT compliances.

Education and Training

Bachelor of Science: Chemistry June 2012 Texas Tech University, City, State

Certifications

HACCP Practitioner - SQF

Internal Auditing - NSF

Skills

Wet chemistry, Calibration, Continuous Improvement, data entry, Good Lab Practices, Instrumental Analysis, First Article Inspection, Internal Auditing, Quality Hold Inventory Control, Laboratory Information Management System, Logging materials, Procedure Writing, protocols, Trend Analysis, Trouble shooting, troubleshooting,